Finding Aid for Volney H. Jones Papers 1909-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Volney H. Jones papers 1909-1979, 1930-1979
Jones, Volney Hurt, 1903-
8 linear feet
Volney H. Jones was a leading ethnobotanist and served as Curator of Ethnology at the University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology from 1945 to 1969. The papers include correspondence with ethnobotanists and anthropologists, including Edward F. Castetter and Leslie A. White, administrative files, biographical information on anthropologists, teaching files for Jones' courses within the Department of Anthropology, and notes for unpublished textbooks on ethnobotany. The papers also include correspondence with Chase S. Osborn, Stellanova B. Osborn, and Milo M. Quaife concerning a project to establish a Friends of the Michigan Indian organization, and correspondence and reports from Ted Bank concerning the University of Michigan expeditions to the Aleutian Islands.
851542 Aa 2
Sponsor: This finding aid is a product of a project supported by a grant awarded to the Bentley Historical Library and University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology in 2002 by the Division of Preservation and Access of the National Endowment for the Humanities, an independent federal agency.
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The majority of the papers (donor no. 9273 ) were transferred by the University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology in 2003. One folder of previously processed correspondence (donor no. 4628 ) was integrated into the papers.
The papers are open without restriction.
Volney Hurt Jones was born on April 30, 1903 in Comanche, Texas. He received an Associate in Science certificate from North Texas Agricultural College in 1927 and a B.A. in agriculture from Texas A&M; University in 1929. He then enrolled in the graduate program in the Department of Biology at the University of New Mexico, studying ethnobotany under Edward Castetter. Jones was awarded a master's degree in 1931.
In 1931, Jones left New Mexico to take a position as a student assistant in the Ethnobotanical Laboratory at the University of Michigan's Museum of Anthropology, working under Melvin Gilmore. With Gilmore in poor health, Jones was called upon to take over much of the work of the lab almost from the earliest days of his appointment. When Gilmore died in 1940, Jones became head of the lab and the museum's ethnographic collections, though he did not receive the full official title of Curator of Ethnology until 1945. Jones also taught in the Department of Anthropology, and was particularly known for his popular course on Native Americans. He was named assistant professor in 1945 and associate professor in 1952. Jones held these positions until his retirement in 1969. Jones spent his entire professional career at Michigan, though he took a fifteen-month leave of absence from the university to work in rubber production in Haiti during World War II.
The Ethnobotanical Laboratory served as a central facility for researchers throughout the country to send ethnological and archaeological plant specimens for taxonomic identification and analysis. This work brought Jones in contact with many of the major figures in the fields of archaeology and ethnobotany, and the analyses from the over 350 specimen reports Jones authored were cited countless times in field reports and publications (though Jones did not always receive proper attribution).
Jones conceived of ethnobotany as much broader than simple identification and listing of plant samples, however. His ecological perspective on the field, which he defined as "the study of the interrelationships between primitive man and plants," was instilled in the many students he mentored over the years and shaped its future development. Jones was particularly notable for his pioneering work in paleoethnobotany; little recognized at the time they were done, Jones' studies of the biological remains of archaeological sites received renewed attention through the ongoing research of his former students, particularly Richard Yarnell, Vorsila Bohrer, and Richard Ford. In the late 1960s, Jones work at the University also involved consulting for a series of TV productions on Native Americans done in collaboration with the University of Michigan Law School and Television Center called Silent Heritage.
Jones' interest in Native Americans extended to his activities outside of the university as well. He served on several state commissions related to Native Americans in Michigan. He was also president of the Memorial to the American Indian Foundation, an organization formed in Ann Arbor in 1953 with an eye to erecting a sculpture in Gallup, New Mexico. Jones was also sometimes called upon to use his ethnobotanical knowledge in unusual ways, including serving as an expert witness from the 1940s to 1960s in the identification of marijuana plants for criminal cases.
Jones was married to Joyce Hedrick, a mycologist, from 1933 until her death in 1978. They had one son, Alan, born in 1937. Jones died on December 12, 1982 in Ann Arbor.
Related Resources
Additional biographical information about Volney Jones may be found in The Nature and Status of Ethnobotany, edited by Richard I. Ford, University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology Anthropological Papers no. 67, and "Volney Hurt Jones, 1930-1982" by C. Wesley Cowan, American Antiquity 53(3), 1988, pages 455-460.
For further information about the Ethnobotanical Laboratory, see "The Ethnobotanical Laboratory at the University of Michigan" by Melvin R. Gilmore, published as University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology Occasional Contributions, no. 1, as well as the Melvin R. Gilmore Papers, available at the Bentley Library.
The Volney H. Jones Papers include correspondence with ethnobotanists and anthropologists, including Edward F. Castetter and Leslie A. White, administrative files, biographical information on anthropologists, teaching files for Jones' courses within the Department of Anthropology, and notes for unpublished textbooks on ethnobotany. The papers also include correspondence with Chase S. Osborn, Stellanova B. Osborn, and Milo M. Quaife concerning a project to establish a Friends of the Michigan Indian organization, and correspondence and reports from Ted Bank concerning the University of Michigan expeditions to the Aleutian Islands. The Jones papers are comprised of eight series: Correspondence, Administrative Files, Biographies and Bibliographies, Teaching Files, Culture Areas and Ethnobotany Textbook Files, Hopi Research Files and Maize Research.
Subjects:
Jones, Volney H. (Volney Hurt), 1903-1982; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Anthropology.; University of Michigan. Museum of Anthropology.; University of Michigan. Ethnobotanical Laboratory.; Ethnobotany.; Paleoethnobotany.; Anthropology--Bio-bibliography.; Anthropology--Study and teaching.; Indians of North America--Michigan.; Indians of North America--Ethnobotany.; Aleutian Islands (Alaska)
Contributors:
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Osborn, Stellanova, 1894-1988.; Quaife, Milo Milton, 1880-1959.; Gilmore, Melvin R. (Melvin Randolph), 1868-1940.; Bank, Ted.; Castetter, Edward Franklin, 1896-; White, Leslie A., 1900-1975.
Genre/Form:
Field notes.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence series, 1930-1979 (2 linear feet), contains Jones' incoming and outgoing personal and professional correspondence, spanning from 1930 to 1979. The files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with files of miscellaneous correspondence at the end of each letter range.
  Much of Jones' professional correspondence consists of discussions with other ethnobotanists and anthropologists about their laboratory research, field work, and analysis of organic samples. Jones' correspondence also serves as documentation of the beginnings of the field of paleoethnobotany. Correspondents of note include Edward Castetter (Jones' mentor at the University of New Mexico) and Leslie White. The files for Theodore (Ted) Bank include substantial information on a University of Michigan expedition to the Aleutians in the late 1940s. The dating of material from Sandia Cave is discussed in correspondence with Frank Hibben and Alex Krieger. Correspondence with Chase S. Osborn, Stellanova B. Osborn, and Milo M. Quaife concerning a project to establish a Friends of the Michigan Indian organization can be found in the Stellanova Osborn folder.
  - Agogino, George 1953-1959 (Box 1)
  - American Museum of Natural History 1942 (Box 1)
  - Amerind Foundation 1945-1952 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Edgar 1941-1954 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Robert 1942-1958 (Box 1)
  - Aveleyra A. de Anda, Luis 1954-1959 (Box 1)
  - A-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Bailey, L.H. 1935-1940 (Box 1)
  - Bank, Theodore (Ted) 1948-1975, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bartoo, Harriette 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - Beaudoin, Kenneth L. 1953 (Box 1)
  - Blake, S.F. 1936-1939 (Box 1)
  - Bohrer, Vorsila L. 1953-1970 (Box 1)
  - Braidwood, Robert 1950 (Box 1)
  - Brew, J.O. 1936-1951 (Box 1)
  - Brigham, Edward M. 1940 (Box 1)
  - Brown, William L. 1954-1956 (Box 1)
  - Bureau of American Ethnology 1940-1960 (Box 1)
  - B-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - California, University of 1937-1952 (Box 1)
  - Carter, George F. 1945-1950 (Box 1)
  - Castetter, Edward F. 1933-1975 (Box 1)
  - Chase, Agnes 1930-1939 (Box 1)
  - Chicago Natural History Museum 1945 (Box 1)
  - Clements Library 1947-1949 (Box 1)
  - Colley, Charles C. 1978 (Box 1)
  - Colton, Harold S. 1934-1950 (Box 1)
  - Conklin, Harold C. 1955-1961 (Box 1)
  - Cranbrook Institute of Science 1940-1969 (Box 1)
  - Cutler, Hugh C. 1948-1971 (Box 1)
  - C-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Densmore, Frances 1945 (Box 1)
  - Denver Art Museum 1936-1944 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Children's Museum 1940-1949 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Historical Museum 1945-1957 (Box 1)
  - Deuel, Thorne 1939-1950 (Box 1)
  - Di Peso, Charles C. 1953-1955 (Box 1)
  - Dockstader, Frederick J. 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Dodge, Ernest 1947-1949 (Box 1)
  - Dragoo, Don W. 1963 (Box 1)
  - Dutton, Bertha P. 1939-1967 (Box 1)
  - D-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Elmore, Francis 1936-1947 (Box 1)
  - Euler, Robert C. 1953-1976 (Box 1)
  - Ewing, George H. 1967 (Box 1)
  - E-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Fenton, William N. 1933-1966 (Box 1)
  - Fonner, Robert L. 1950-1962 (Box 1)
  - Ford, Richard I. 1969-1979 (Box 1)
  - Fosberg, F.R. 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Fowler, Melvin L. 1952-1961 (Box 1)
  - F-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Galinat, Wilton C. 1962 (Box 1)
  - Gallup Indian Community Center 1966 (Box 1)
  - Gibbons, Thomas A. 1963-1966 (Box 1)
  - Gilmore, Melvin R. 1934-1942 (Box 1)
  - Goodwin Collection 1956-1964 (Box 1)
  - Guthe, Carl E. 1940-1943 (Box 1)
  - G-Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Haag, William G. 1940-1976 (Box 1)
  - Hack, John T. 1938-1944 (Box 2)
  - Hargrave, Lyndon L. 1964 (Box 2)
  - Harrington, M.R. 1944-1945 (Box 2)
  - Haury, Emil W. 1936-1948 (Box 2)
  - Heizer, Robert F. 1941-1952 (Box 2)
  - Hibben, Frank C. 1953-1963 (Box 2)
  - Hodge, F.W. 1945-1948 (Box 2)
  - Howard, James H. 1954-1957 (Box 2)
  - H-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Irvine, Frederick Robert 1958-1959 (Box 2)
  - Jackson, Henry 1973 (Box 2)
  - Jennings, Jesse D. 1938-1954 (Box 2)
  - Judd, Neil M. 1936 (Box 2)
  - J-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Kaplan, Lawrence 1956-1958 (Box 2)
  - Kent, Barry C. 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Kidder, Alfred V. 1937-1947 (Box 2)
  - Krieger, Alex 1946-1955 (Box 2)
  - K-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Lambert, Robert J. 1952-1956 (Box 2)
  - Leechman, Douglas 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  - Lieberman, Leonard 1966 (Box 2)
  - Lippincott, Sallie undated (Box 2)
  - L-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Malkin, Borys 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - Martin, Paul S. 1941-1960 (Box 2)
  - Mason, Carol Irwin undated (Box 2)
  - Masters, William M. 1950-1953 (Box 2)
  - McKern, W.C. 1936 (Box 2)
  - Mera, H.P. 1934 (Box 2)
  - Merrill, William L. 1975-1977 (Box 2)
  - Michigan State College 1947-1950 (Box 2)
  - Morris, Earl H. 1949-1954 (Box 2)
  - Murchie, W. R. 1967 (Box 2)
    (Flint lectures)
  - Museum of Northern Arizona 1932-1975 (Box 2)
  - Museum of the American Indian 1936-1961 (Box 2)
  - M-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Nabhan, Gary 1977-1979 (Box 2)
  - National Park Service 1937-1960 (Box 2)
  - National Science Foundation
    - General 1953-1964 (Box 2)
    - Final Report on GS-659 1966-1971 (Box 2)
  - New Mexico, Museum of 1937-1959 (Box 2)
  - N-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Orchard, W.C. 1933-1936 (Box 2)
  - Osborn, Stellanova 1945-1948 (Box 2)
    (re: project to establish a Friends of the Michigan Indian organization)
  - O-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Peebles, R.H. 1940 (Box 2)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art 1950 (Box 2)
  - Pohrt, Richard A. 1960-1979 (Box 2)
  - Pratt, Peter P. 1964 (Box 2)
  - P-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Quaife, Milo M. 1941-1948 (Box 2)
  - Quimby, George I. 1935-1949 (Box 2)
  - Reagan, A.B. 1935 (Box 2)
  - Reed, Erik K. 1949-1955 (Box 2)
  - Reeves, R.G. 1935-1953 (Box 2)
  - Reid, Russell 1938 (Box 2)
  - Reiter, Paul and Winifred 1936-1953 (Box 2)
  - Roberts, Wilmer C. 1939-1952 (Box 2)
  - Rouse, Irving 1942-1949 (Box 2)
  - Rousseau, Jacques 1932-1962 (Box 2)
  - R-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Saginaw Museum 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Sauer, Jonathan 1947-1953 (Box 2)
  - Sayles, E.B. 1937-1942 (Box 2)
  - Schneider, Mary Jane 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - Schultes, Richard E. 1937-1978 (Box 2)
  - Scott, Donald 1937-1946 (Box 2)
  - Shacklette, Hansford T. 1961 (Box 2)
  - Shetrone, H.C. 1934-1942 (Box 2)
  - Sirrine, Emma F. 1936-1938 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Hale G. 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Smith, Preston 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - Southwest Museum 1935-1958 (Box 2)
  - Speck, F.G. 1934-1949 (Box 2)
  - Stubbs, Stanley 1946-1949 (Box 2)
  - S-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Tantaquidgeon, Gladys and Harold 1934-1937 (Box 2)
  - Toulouse, Joseph H. 1942-1950 (Box 2)
  - T-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - United States Department of Agriculture 1934-1936 (Box 2)
  - United States Government Printing Office Superintendent of Documents 1950 (Box 2)
  - Vestal, Paul A. 1938-1945 (Box 2)
  - Voegelin, Carl and Erminie 1938-1948 (Box 2)
  - V-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Washington, University of 1952-1954 (Box 2)
  - Webb, Malcolm C. undated (Box 2)
  - Webb, William S. 1934-1939 (Box 2)
  - Wedel, Waldo R. 1946-1979 (Box 2)
  - Whitaker, Thomas A. 1947-1952 (Box 2)
  - White, Leslie, A. 1937-1971 (Box 2)
  - Whiting, Alfred F. 1935-1965 (Box 2)
  - Wilder, Charles G. 1951 (Box 2)
  - Will, George F. 1941-1942 (Box 2)
  - Williams, U.H. 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Wissler, Clark 1936 (Box 2)
  - Witthoft, John 1946-1948, undated (Box 2)
  - Wittrock, G.L. 1938-1942 (Box 2)
  - Wright, Ross Pier 1942-1947 (Box 2)
  - W-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Yanovsky, E. 1933-1939 (Box 2)
  - Yarnell, Richard A. 1962-1967 (Box 2)
  - Y-Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Administrative Files
  The Administrative Files series, 1953-1976 (0.5 linear feet), includes materials on a National Science Foundation grant, Jones' reviews of grant proposals, and administrative information related to the Museum of Anthropology.
  - Hunt Botanical Library 1971 (Box 3)
    (includes photo)
  - Memorial to the American Indian Foundation circa 1953 (Box 3)
  - Prospectus on Moving, Reorganization and Rehabilitation of the Museum of Anthropology 1963 (Box 3)
  - Regional Patterns in Pueblo Ethnobotany (National Science Foundation grant)
    - Budget and Accounting 1965-1968 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with NSF 1964-1970 (Box 3)
    - Karen Ford 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - Richard Ford
      - Correspondence 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Field Notes 1965 (Box 3)
    - Marjorie Lambert-Correspondence 1965 (Box 3)
    - Proposal 1964 (Box 3)
    - Report on Excavation of Jemez Cave 1965 (Box 3)
  - Reviews of Grant Proposals 1960-1976, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Schepp Foundation 1966 (Box 3)
  - Society for American Archaeology undated (Box 3)
- Biographies and Bibliographies, bulk compiled 1950s-1970s
  The Biographies and Bibliographies series, bulk 1950s-1970s (1.25 linear feet), contains research materials, bibliographies, and biographical sketches for prominent anthropologists, with particular focus on ethnographers. While Jones compiled much of the supporting research himself from the 1950s to 1970s, many of the brief biographical sketches were written by students in Jones' Department of Anthropology course, Anthropology 557: Aboriginal Cultures of North America. The contents of the files range from a single citation to an obituary or published biography to a full biographical sketch. The most comprehensive of the sketches is one of James B. Griffin, written by Jones with handwritten amendments by Griffin. A few of the files include correspondence concerning Jones' research into a particular biographical subject.
  - Abel, Annie Heloise (Box 3)
  - Adams, Inez (Box 3)
  - Adney, Edwin Tappan (Box 3)
  - Alexander, Hartley Burr (Box 3)
  - Amsden, Charles Avery (Box 3)
  - Bandelier, Adolph F.A. (Box 3)
  - Barbeau, Marius (Box 3)
  - Barrett, Samuel Alfred (Box 3)
  - Bartlett, John Russell (Box 3)
  - Bartlett, Katharine (Box 3)
  - Beaglehole, Ernest (Box 3)
  - Beaglehole, Pearl S. (Box 3)
  - Beals, Ralph Leon (Box 3)
  - Benedict, Ruth Fulton (Box 3)
  - Benham, G.W. and Benham Exploring Expedition (Box 3)
  - Birket-Smith, Kaj (Box 3)
  - Boas, Franz (Box 3)
  - Boyle, David (Box 3)
  - Brown, G. Gordon (Box 3)
  - Bunzel, Ruth (Box 3)
  - Bushnell, David Ives (Box 3)
  - Caldwell, Joseph Ralston (Box 3)
  - Carr, Lucien (Box 3)
  - Catlin, George (Box 3)
  - Chamberlain, Alexander F. (Box 3)
  - Chapman, Kenneth M. (Box 3)
  - Clover, Elzada U. (Box 3)
  - Cole, Fay-Cooper (Box 3)
  - Colton, Harold S. (Box 3)
  - Colton, Mary-Russell F. (Box 3)
  - Cooper, John Montgomery (Box 3)
  - Cowie, Isaac (Box 3)
  - Curtain, Jeremiah (Box 3)
  - Curtis, Edward S. (Box 3)
  - Dall, William H. (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Daniel S. (Box 3)
  - Davis, Edward H. (Box 3)
  - Dawson, George M. (Box 3)
  - de Laguna, Frederica (Box 3)
  - Deans, J. (Box 3)
  - Dellenbaugh, Frederick S. (Box 3)
  - Dixon, Roland Burrage (Box 3)
  - Dorsey, George A. (Box 3)
  - Dorsey, James Owen (Box 3)
  - Douglas, Frederic Huntington (Box 3)
  - Driver, Harold Edson (Box 3)
  - Du Ponceau, Peter (Box 3)
  - Dubois, Constance Goddard (Box 3)
  - Dunbar, John Brown (Box 3)
  - Dusenberry, Verne (Box 3)
  - Dutton, Bertha P. (Box 3)
  - Eggan, Dorothy Way (Box 3)
  - Eggan, Fred (Box 3)
  - Eells, Myron (Box 3)
  - Ellis, Florence Hawley (Box 3)
  - Emmons, G.T. (Box 3)
  - Ewers, John C. (Box 3)
  - Farrand, Livingston (Box 3)
  - Fenton, William N. (Box 3)
  - Fisher, Reginald G. (Box 3)
  - Fletcher, Alice C. (Box 3)
  - Ford, James Alfred (Box 3)
  - Fowke, Gerard (Box 3)
  - Freeman, John F. (Box 3)
  - Frison, George C. (Box 3)
  - Gallatin, Abraham Alphonse Albert (Box 3)
  - Gatschet, Albert Samuel (Box 3)
  - Gayton, Anna H. (Box 3)
  - Gibbs, George (Box 3)
  - Gifford, E.W. (Box 3)
  - Goddard, Pliny Earle (Box 3)
  - Goggin, John M. (Box 3)
  - Goldenweiser, Alexander A. (Box 3)
  - Goldfrank, Esther S. (Box 3)
  - Goodwin, Grenville (Box 3)
  - Greenman, Emerson F. (Box 3)
  - Gregory, Herbert E. (Box 3)
  - Griffin, James B. (Box 3)
    (includes Griffin's corrections)
  - Grinnell, George Bird (Box 3)
  - Gunther, Erna (Box 3)
  - Haas, Mary Rosamond (Box 3)
  - Haeberlin, Herman Karl (Box 3)
  - Haile, Father Berard (Box 3)
  - Hale, Horatio E. (Box 3)
  - Hallowell, A. Irving (Box 3)
  - Harrington, Mark Raymond (Box 3)
  - Havard, Valery (Box 3)
  - Heizer, Robert F. (Box 3)
  - Henshaw, Henry Wetherbee (Box 3)
  - Hewett, Edgar Lee (Box 3)
  - Hewitt, John N. B. (Box 3)
  - Heye, George G. (Box 3)
  - Hilger, M. Inez (Box 3)
  - Hill, Willard Williams (Box 3)
  - Hinsdale, Wilbert B. (Box 3)
  - Hodge, Frederick W. (Box 3)
  - Hodge, Mary G. (Box 3)
  - Hodson, Thomas Callan (Box 3)
  - Hoebel, E. Adamson (Box 3)
  - Hoffman, Walter J. (Box 3)
  - Holmes, William Henry (Box 3)
  - Hoover, J.W. (Box 3)
  - Hrdlicka, Ales (Box 3)
  - Hudson, J.W. (Box 3)
  - Humphrey, Norman Daymond (Box 3)
  - Hunt, George (Box 3)
  - Jackson, William H. (Box 4)
  - Jacobs, Melville (Box 4)
  - James, George Wharton (Box 4)
  - Jenks, Albert E. (Box 4)
  - Jenness, Diamond (Box 4)
  - Jesup, Morris K. (Box 4)
  - Jochelson, Waldemar (Box 4)
  - Jones, William (Box 4)
  - Joseph, Alice (Box 4)
  - Kaemlein, Wilma (Box 4)
  - Kane, Paul (Box 4)
  - Kelly, Isabel T. (Box 4)
  - Kennard, Edward A. (Box 4)
  - King, Clarence (Box 4)
  - Kluckhohn, Clyde (Box 4)
  - Kroeber, Alfred L. (Box 4)
  - La Farge, Oliver (Box 4)
  - Lafitau, Joseph F. (Box 4)
  - La Flesche, Francis (Box 4)
  - Lancaster, James A. (Box 4)
  - Landes, Ruth (Box 4)
  - Lantis, Margaret (Box 4)
  - Leighton, Alexander Hamilton and Dorothy Cross (Box 4)
  - Linton, Ralph (Box 4)
  - Loeb, Edwin Meyer (Box 4)
  - Lowie, Robert H. (Box 4)
  - Luhrs, Dorothy (Box 4)
  - Lummis, Charles Fletcher (Box 4)
  - Mallery, Garrick (Box 4)
  - Martin, Paul S. (Box 4)
  - Mason, John A. (Box 4)
  - Mason, Otis T. (Box 4)
  - McGee, W.J. (Box 4)
  - McGregor, John C. (Box 4)
  - McGuire, Joseph D. (Box 4)
  - McIlwraith, Thomas Forsyth (Box 4)
  - McKennan, Robert A. (Box 4)
  - McLeod, William Christie (Box 4)
  - McNitt, Frank (Box 4)
  - Mead, Margaret (Box 4)
  - Mekeel, Haviland Scudder (Box 4)
  - Michelson, Truman (Box 4)
  - Mindeleff, Cosmos and Victor (Box 4)
  - Miner, Horace M. (Box 4)
  - Mook, Maurice Allison (Box 4)
  - Morgan, Lewis Henry (Box 4)
  - Morris, Earl H. (Box 4)
  - Murdock, George P. (Box 4)
  - Murie, James R. (Box 4)
  - Nelson, Nels C. (Box 4)
  - Nusbaum, Jesse (Box 4)
  - Ober, Frederick Albion (Box 4)
  - Opler, Morris Edward (Box 4)
  - Owens, John G. (Box 4)
  - Parsons, Elsie W. Clews (Box 4)
  - Park, Willard Z. (Box 4)
  - Parker, Arthur C. (Box 4)
  - Peet, Stephen D. (Box 4)
  - Pepper, George H. (Box 4)
  - Pilling, James C. (Box 4)
  - Pinkley, Homer V. (Box 4)
  - Powell, John Wesley (Box 4)
  - Provinse, John H. (Box 4)
  - Putnam, Frederick Ward (Box 4)
  - Radin, Paul (Box 4)
  - Rappaport, Roy A. (Box 4)
  - Reichard, Gladys A. (Box 4)
  - Rink, Henrick (Box 4)
  - Robert, Frank H.H. (Box 4)
  - Russell, Frank (Box 4)
  - Sapir, Edward (Box 4)
  - Schaeffer, Claude Everett (Box 4)
  - Schenck, William Egbert (Box 4)
  - Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe (Box 4)
  - Setzler, Frank Maryl (Box 4)
  - Shufeldt, R.W. (Box 4)
  - Simms, Stephen Chapman (Box 4)
  - Skarland, Ivar (Box 4)
  - Skinner, Alanson B. (Box 4)
  - Slotki, James Sydney (Box 4)
  - Smith, C. Earle (Box 4)
  - Smith, Erminne A. (Box 4)
  - Smith, Huron H. (Box 4)
  - Speck, Frank Gouldsmith (Box 4)
  - Spicer, Edward Holland (Box 4)
  - Spier, Leslie (Box 4)
  - Spinden, Herbert J. (Box 4)
  - Starr, Betty Warren (Box 4)
  - Starr, Frederick (Box 4)
  - Stefansson, Vilhjalmur (Box 4)
  - Stephen, Alexander M. (Box 4)
  - Stevenson, Matilda C. (Box 4)
  - Steward, Julian H. (Box 4)
  - Stewart, Omer C. (Box 4)
  - Stewart, T. Dale (Box 4)
  - Stirling, Matthew W. (Box 4)
  - Strong, William Duncan (Box 4)
  - Swadesh, Morris (Box 4)
  - Swan, James G. (Box 4)
  - Swanton, John Reed (Box 4)
  - Tanner, Clara Lee (Box 4)
  - Tecumseh (Box 4)
  - Teit, James A. (Box 4)
  - Ten Kate, Herman F.C. (Box 4)
  - Thomas, Cyrus (Box 4)
  - Titiev, Mischa (Box 4)
  - Townsend, Charles H. (Box 4)
  - Turney-High, Harry Holbert (Box 4)
  - Underhill, Ruth M. (Box 4)
  - Vavilov, Nikolai Ivanovich (Box 4)
  - Voegelin, Carl F. (Box 4)
  - Voegelin, Erminie W. (Box 4)
  - Voth, Heinrich R. (Box 4)
  - Vroman, A.C. (Box 4)
  - Walker, James R. (Box 4)
  - Wallis, Wilson Dallam (Box 4)
  - Waterman, Thomas T. (Box 4)
  - Waugh, F.W. (Box 4)
  - Wedel, Waldo R. (Box 4)
  - Weltfish, Gene (Box 4)
  - White, Leslie A. (Box 4)
  - Whitman, William (Box 4)
  - Whorf, Benjamin Lee (Box 4)